# Hakan Aksuman

İzmir, Turkey

h.aksuman@gmail.com

+90 553 158-81-66

linkedin.com/in/hakanaksuman

https://haksuman.github.io/ (Personal Portfolio)

### Summary

Currently working for United Nations as a front-end developer and interested in the coding user interfaces on the web. Coding has been a hobby in my university years, which turned into passion driving me to enhance my knowledge about responsive web design. Since I am an attentive self-learner and flexible initiative-taker, I always implement practical skills in programming to solve business problems. Swiftly responding to changing needs of an organization, quick self-learning, experience with React & Typescript, strong communication and people skills are abilities which underpin me as a software developer.

#### **Experience**



### **Front-end Developer**

**United Nations** 

Jul 2022 - Present (4 months +)

Front-end design of the United Nations' radar and user interface.

- Developed front-end user interface by using React and Typescript.
- Worked with project management and applied agile methodologies with using Kanban board.
- Implement the features and user interfaces of new and existing products with JavaScript.
- Streamlined software development testing practices throughout the team.
- Managed version control operation operations with Git.



#### **Data Analyst**

**United Nations** 

May 2022 - Jul 2022 (3 months)

Al powered Knowledge Base Development

- Web scraping to various domains for knowledge-based Al development by using Python Beautifulsoup
- Developed automated headless web application tests with Selenium-webdrive and improved project time to get related data from 6 months to 3 months.
- Performed data cleaning operations for obtained data with NumPy and Pandas.

## **Project Control Engineer**

Renaissance Heavy Industries

Jun 2021 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

Arctic LNG-2 / Murmansk, Russia

- Built a full-stack web application which reduced response time for issues by 10% to manage teams while tracking issues for ongoing project with using React.js, Typescript and Django.
- Creating data pipelines and connections with big data sets.
- Automated reporting progress by developing automated reports with Python and Power BI.
- Developed automated file management tools and slash required time for foldering by 85%.

#### Skills

- Agile Methodologies
  Front-end Development
  Data Analysis
  React.js
  JavaScript
  Python
  HTML
  CSS
- Software Development
  Responsive Web Design
  Typescript
  Rest API
  Django
  Project Management

#### **Education**



# Orta Doğu Teknik Üniversitesi / Middle East Technical University

Bachelor's degree, Civil Engineering (GPA:3.20/4.00)